Agah, Anthony

Email: agah.anthony@gmail.com Phone(M): +234 803 763 4249

As a very passionate product geek, I have worked in an enabling environment where hard work, smart work, innovation, creativity, and diligence are highly appreciated in order to achieve desired goals in business. I'm open to new ideas and tackling of new challenges while developing and learning in the process; as they are keys to being a top talent to any organization, firm or company I get to work with during my career path journey.

Education

2013 - 2017

B.Sc., Management *University of Nigeria*.

Work Experience

15/11/2021 - Present

15/07/2019 - 24/12/2021

01/08/2019 - 09/06/2021

25/07/2020 - 01/03/2021

Lead Product Manager

Lazerpay

- Created the start-up's first product structure.
- Led the product team to its beta launch and official launch in four months.
- Built the donations feature for NGOs, Fiat Pav-out for merchants, Website, KYC/KYB, Merchant Dashboard which comprises of the payment links and buttons.

Lead & Senior PM (Customer Engagement Pod) *Sabi*

- Led a team of eleven individuals (senior software engineers. QAs, designers & product mangers) to meet the monthly and quarterly product initiative targets laid out by the Head of Product.
- Built products like Sell Online, Help & Support, and Payment Reminders to optimize business operations for over 150,000 merchants.
- Built MvShop feature on the app that enables merchants create sales records worth of \$1.2 billion in less than six months of launch.

Training & Development Analyst

West Africa Vocational Education

- Generated and implemented actionable insights from the impact of the knowledge acquired by trainees in various cohorts.
- Ensured that the nudge experiments with regards to training and curriculum development were in line with the expectations of organization's employer partner's needs.

Product Designer/Manager

BingFood

- Designed and managed the development process of the app.
- Conducted user research that informed the design decisions I took in deploying the app.
- Provided feedback to the engineering team and ensures both internal and external stakeholders are part of every stage of the product development cycle.

15/01/2019 - 01/06/2019

Project Manager

Ogwugo

- Coordinated the riders and made sure their order delivery processes were effective by employing some agile methodologies.
- Managed the platform for taking, processing and delivering orders.

12/12/2017 - 01/11/2018

Marketing Executive

Raadaa

- Come up with strategies that would drive sales so as generate revenue.
- Met and convinced 3 clients in various research institutions to use our online platform.
- Fill monthly reports from weekly and daily reports submitted by other team members while synergizing with the CEO based on assessment gathered.

01/03/2017 - 01/02/2018

Co-founder & CPO

Agrommerce

- Developed the business plans, product strategies, market strategies and business models of the company.
- Scaled the operations of the team in developing a minimum lovable product (MLP) for users.

03/2015 - 01/2020

Executive Director

Business Students' Club (BSC)

- Created an enabling environment for business students to attain academic excellence and activate innate potentials through active learning techniques.
- Help business students to learn theoretically and execute practically their acquired knowledge in their field of study through engagement meetings, trainings, research presentations and company visits.

08/2012 - 12/2012

Undergraduate Logistics Intern

Nigerian Breweries

- Carried out the arrangement of sales files for easy referencing when the need be.
- Reported any findings to the logistics executive and suggested a better a solution to avoid future occurrences.

03/2011 - 02/2012

Human Resource Manager

AIESEC Enugu

- Created a member education circle and local committee development plan for members including in house training, slumber meetings and webinars while development are being tracked.
- Planned the recruitment and effective allocation of 500 members into different functional areas to aid their development and achieve desired results.

06/2011

Dual Campus Event Coordinator

Google Powered Academics

- Organized a Google event with more than 500 delegates in attendance at both campus with different locations and developed session presentations for the student ambassadors.
- Guided the participants through the usage of some Google products during the event like Google maps, AdSense, forms, search and mail.

03/2010 - 04/2011

Team Leader Talent Management

AIESEC Enuqu

Reported, assisted and conducted all activity as regards to

membership development, trainings, conferences, performance management and appraisal to the Vice President Talent Management for further assessment and analysis.

Training/Certifications

02/2020 - 05/2021

Product Management

ProductDive

- Learnt about how to build products that succeed through deploying various strategies and frameworks.
- Presented a capstone project and collaborate with fellow PMs in the training review and develop products.

05/2020 - 03/2021

UI/UX Design

Stutern

- Participated in guest sessions with design leads of some of the most prominent and funded tech startups in Africa like Paystack, Opay and TeamApt.
- Worked in teams for group live projects, collaborated with developers to create a viable product, worked on solo projects that solve mind-boggling problems and presented design topics of interest during peer presentations.

08/2013 - 10/2013

Delegate/Participant

Commonwealth's Developing Young Leaders Program

- Involved with 2000 youth leaders over the world converging to interact online on business, societal and leadership topics.
- Assigned and completed tasks on leadership weekly while participating in solution forums to tackle global issues.

Jira, Trello, Figma, Mixpanel, Hotjar, AdobeXD, Whimsical, Miro, SalesForce, Microsoft word, Microsoft power point,

Microsoft Excel, Google docs, good usage of the internet,

system analytic skills, presentation skills, communication skills, negotiation skills.

Professional skills/tools

English & Pidgin (excellent).

Languages Spoken

Referees available on demand